MENGMEI TU

mmtu0290@gmail.com · 608-630-0288 | Bellevue, WA

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/mengmei-tu · GitHub: https://github.com/mmeii · Portfolio: https://iammei.com

Full stack web developer leveraging 5+ years background in Accounting with a passion for building projects from ideation to execution. A mobilizer who loves acquiring new skills and tackling new challenges. Strong emphasis on working collaboratively in teams to deliver optimal results.

EDUCATION

Certificate, Full Stack Web Developer · Ohio State University	2020 - 2021
Master of Science in Accounting University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee	2013 - 2014
Bachelor of Business Administration University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee	2008 - 2013

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, ES6, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Bumla, Responsive Web Design, React, AJAX, MySQL, Sequelize, NoSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Webpack, PWA, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, Git, GitHub, Heroku, NPM, REST APIs, Postman, DevTools

PROJECTS

LibMaker 3000 · https://makeyourmadlib.herokuapp.com/

January 2021 - February 2021

Node, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars.js, Bootstrap

- Developed a mad libs generator that takes user input and plugs into a predefined story template after parsing
- Oversaw the development of the application and collaborated with a team of five
- Debugged to ensure a seamless front-end to back-end server communication
- Conducted code reviews with other developers

Todo List · https://iammei.com/react-todo-list/

January 2021

React, Node

- Built a CRUD todo list with React hooks that lets users add, update or delete their todos
- Implemented glassmorphism user interface to enhance user experience
- Incorporated localStorage to save user inputs for managing the todos

 $\textbf{Employee Management Tool} \cdot \underline{\text{https://github.com/mmeii/employee-management-system}}$

January 2021

Node, MySQL, Inquirer.js

- Built a command-line CMS with inquirer to view and manage the departments, roles and employees
- Integrated MySQL database with relational tables to store and query employee information

Weather Dashboard · https://iammei.com/weather-dashboard/

November 2020

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, Moment.js, AJAX, OpenWeather API

- Designed a weather web application that provides weather forecasts based on user search and saves searches
- Created jQuery functions to pull data with API calls to retrieve weather information

EXPERIENCE

Tax Compliance Accountant · ProService Hawaii

2018 - 2020

Assisted development team for new accounting system migration, mitigating risks and increasing efficiency

Accountant · State of Wisconsin

2015 - 2018

Accelerated new system implementation conducting training for 100+ employees and creating SQL reports